

Matthew Krenik Engineer and Developer



US Citizen



Austin, TX



(+1) 469-878-5174



mkrenik.github.io



m-krenik@hotmail.com

About me ——

I am an entrepreneurial-minded engineer with 7 years of professional experience in hardware and software development. I enjoy working on startups and products that create significant value. In my free time, I enjoy playing piano, basketball, mountain biking, rock climbing, and skiing.

Skills —

Software:

Top: C, C++, Linux, IoT

Mid: Android, OpenCV, Javascript

Low: Python, C#, MATLAB

Electrical:

MCUs, Analog / Digital circuit design, Motor control, EDA Tools (KiCAD,

Altium), Soldering

Mechanical:

3D modeling (Solidworks), MIG welding, Wood/metal shop eqpmt.

See website and CV for more details

work experience

2018-2020 Popspots —Sr. Embedded Engineer

Project managed two new HW products from start to finish

- Found, vetted, and worked with HW suppliers/ manufacturers
- Reviewed ME/EE designs and brought in house
- Developed PRD and MRD, and supervised NPI and MP builds Designed and implemented embedded SW and IoT architecture
- Reduced provision time by 85% and increased reliability by 50%

2016-2018 iRobot —Robotics Software Engineer

Supervised assembly line sensor calibration and test software Wrote new robot navigation test, improving code coverage to 80% Worked on features/bugs for robot path planning and state

2012-2015 Vertice Incorporated —Founder

Invented a smart, position-aware hair clipper Wrote and filed eight patents (granted)

Led a team of four engineers to develop working prototypes

Raised >\$60K and had a profitable exit

education

2014-2016 ETH Zurich (#7 by QS World Univ. Rankings in 2019)

M.Sc. in Robotics, Systems, and Controls GPA: 5.76 / 6.0 (Highest distinction)

2011-2013 University of Texas at Dallas

B.Sc. in Electrical Engineering

M.Sc. in Innovation and Entrepreneurship (60% completed)

GPA: 3.99 / 4.0 (Summa Cum Laude)

McDermott Fellowship (full tuition, room+board, stipend)
Goldwater Fellowship (nationwide UG research award)

2009-2011 Texas Academy of Math and Science

Advanced early college program at University of North Texas

GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

select projects

2016 Smart Bed Project

Created bed with sensors and actuators that adapts to user's body pose; modeled system in Simulink and developed optimal control strategies

2015 Feedback for Real-Walking VR

Implemented visual, audio, and haptic feedback mechanisms on a real-walking VR system to prevent unplanned user behavior

other experience

2016 Recurse Center

Pair prog. SW, comp. vision, and machine learning projects

2015 **ABB**—**Software Development Intern**

Developed four industrial demos on Oculus and Leap Motion

2014-2015 **JetBrains** — Product Ambassador

Organized events and code challenges to promote SW products

2012 University of Maine —Research Assistant

Built a low cost harmonic radar system for detecting wood frogs